costadelmar.com 2018-10-02

# Costa Del Mar Privacy Policy

At Costa, we are committed to protecting your privacy and to developing technology that gives you the most powerful and secure online experience. You can travel through most of our site and digital services without giving us any information about yourself. But sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this statement of privacy explains data collection and use in those situations. Please read the complete costadelmar.com privacy statement carefully.

This Privacy was last modified and is effective as of May 25, 2018. Costa Del Mar, Inc. and its affiliated entities (“Costa”, “We” or “us”) under Costa’s Terms of Use. This Privacy Policy applies to information collected on or through the Costa Digital Services to which it is posted. Please read our Privacy Policy carefully to be sure you understand how Costa collects and uses information and under what circumstances Costa shares information about you. Capitalized terms not defined herein have the meaning ascribed to them in the Terms of Use.

**1\. Costa Can Modify This Privacy Policy**

Costa reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time pursuant to the terms and conditions of the Terms of Use.  We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy each time you use the Digital Services so you remain aware of the terms and conditions that apply.

**2\. What Information Costa Collects**

**Anonymous information:**   Our Digital Services capture certain non-personal common technical information automatically.  This information may include your Internet protocol (IP) address, browser type and computer operating system, device type, application software, time and date you visit or use the Digital Services, and traffic patterns and usage data, such as the pages you access, the address of the website that directed you to the Digital Services or the website you visit when you leave the Digital Services. Costa uses this information to understand patterns of site activity, including aggregated user demographics, and to improve the Digital Services so they are more useful for you.

**Personal Information:**   The types of personally identifiable information (“PII”) that may be collected on or through the Digital Services include your name, your status (such as whether you are a consumer, student or journalist), mailing address, email address, title or occupation, and telephone number. Additional PII that may be collected on or through the Digital Services includes, but isn’t limited to:

  * If you are purchasing a product or service, your credit card number, expiration date and security code.
  * If are entering a sweepstake, contest, giveaway or other promotion (each a “Promotion”), your age or birth date.
  * If you are applying for employment, your work authorization information, visa status, desired salary, academic level, employment history including salary, and any other information you include on the resume you upload to the Digital Services.  You may also choose to provide optional information such as race, gender, and whether you are disabled or your Veteran status.
  * If you are participating in a survey, we may ask your gender and age, income, ethnicity, family size and marital status.
  * If you are sharing an article or page of the Digital Services with a third party, the third party email address will also be collected.
  * If you are using a service, information necessary to provide the service you have requested.

**Location Information:**   We may collect information about your location when you access or use the Digital Services. We may collect information regarding your general location using your IP address. If you access or use the Digital Services from a mobile device, we may collect more precise geolocation information from your mobile device. This information may be used to customize certain features of our Digital Services and to provide you with location-based services. This information may also be used to send push notifications, which appear on the display of your mobile device in the form of a badge, alert or banner, and allow mobile applications to send information to your mobile device even when the application is not in use. For information on how to disable geolocation services and/or push notifications on a mobile device, see Section 7 below regarding your Opt-Out Choices.

**3\. Purposes of PII Collection**

We request PII to provide a service, product or information about Costa’s products or services or to complete a transaction. Examples include subscribing to newsletters, emailing a friend an article from the Digital Services, entering a Promotion, participating in training, finding an eyecare professional or doctor, distributor, store or sales consultant, providing information regarding vision, vision care and vision correction, applying for employment, purchasing a product or service, completing online surveys, contacting us with questions or comments, or for product registration.

**4\. Protection of Personal Information Costa Collects**

Although, Costa cannot promise the use of our Digital Services is completely safe, Costa uses standard security measures. Costa urges you to use caution when using the Internet.  This includes not sharing your passwords.

The Digital Services may contain customer reviews, forums and/or message boards and other Online Content.  Please remember that any information disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and you should exercise caution when considering the disclosure of your PII.  You agree that Costa is not responsible for material posted by you or others in these public forums.

**5\. Sharing of PII**

Costa will not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to third parties your PII except as described below or unless Costa provides advance notice as set out in the Terms of Use:

  * **Subsidiaries and Affiliates.**  Costa may transfer PII to its subsidiaries and corporate affiliates, including future subsidiaries and affiliates.
  * **Consultants and Service Providers.**  Costa will disclose PII to third party consultants and service providers (such as providers of hosting, support, maintenance and remedial, repair services, mail delivery services, evaluation data analysis, data cleansing, order fulfillment and shipping, Promotion administration and fulfillment, advertising, marketing and promotional activities, fraud protection and risk reduction, and payment processing and authorization) to the extent that they require access to the databases, or the PII contained in our databases, to provide services to you or Costa.
  * **Joint Promotion Partners.**  Sometimes we conduct joint promotions with third parties.  If you register for one of those joint promotions your information may be collected by both Costa and the third party.  Or, we may give you the option to have us share your information with the promotion partner.  Your information will be used by us and/or by them as described in our posted privacy policies.
  * **Enforcement of Rights/Security.**  Costa reserves the right to release PII (i) when Costa is under legal compulsion to do so (e.g. we have received a subpoena) or Costa otherwise believes that the law requires us to do so, (ii) when Costa believes it is necessary to protect and/or enforce the rights, property interests, or safety of Costa, our users or others, or (iii) as Costa deems necessary to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, prevent fraud and otherwise enforce the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.
  * **Reorganization or Sale of the Company.** In the event that the Costa is merged with or becomes part of another organization, or in the event that Costa is sold or it sells all or substantially all of its assets or is otherwise reorganized, the PII Costa collects will be one of the transferred assets to the acquiring or reorganized entity.
  * **Third-Party Marketing.**  Costa may share your PII with third parties for their marketing purposes.
  * **As Otherwise Allowed by Law.**  Costa may transfer PII to third parties where we are expressly authorized by applicable law to do so.

**6\. Parents and Guardians**

Our Digital Services are meant for adults. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If you are a parent or legal guardian and think your child under the age of 13 has given us information, you can [contact us](https://www.costadelmar.com/us/en/customer-contact/customer-contact.html "Contact Us") to remove the information.

**7\. Opt-Out Choices**

**Emails.**  You can opt out of receiving future promotional emails from Costa by following the unsubscribe procedures indicated in each email. Even if you opt out of receiving promotional emails from Costa, we will send you transaction emails and respond to questions from you. 

**Cookies.**  Costa uses cookies, which are small data files created by a Web server and stored by your browser, to keep track of and enhance certain user activities on our Digital Services such as logging into your account, making a purchase and other user-specific features. You may block or restrict cookies on your computer or device or purge them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences. You should consult the operating instructions that apply to your browser or your mobile device’s user guide for instructions on how to configure your setting to meet your preferences.  Cookies allow you to take advantage of some features or functions of the Digital Services, so if you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you may not be able to use some features of the Digital Services.

**Interest-Based Behavioral Advertising.**  Costa’s advertisements are shown on third party websites, including Google. Costa may use technologies such as cookies and web beacons (also known as action tags, pixels, or transparent GIF files) to help manage online advertising. These technologies are provided by our third party vendor(s) and enable our third party vendor(s) to recognize a unique cookie placed by us (when you accessed the Digital Services) or by our third party vendor(s), or by another advertiser who works with our third party vendor(s). These technologies allow us to learn which advertisements bring users to our Digital Services. They also allow us to collect information about your online activities over time and across third party websites so we can manage advertising effectiveness and provide you with online advertisements, including advertisements on the websites of third parties not affiliated with Costa, more likely to be of interest to you. Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads to you based on your past visits to the Digital Services. With this technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address.  **For more information about online behavioral advertising and your choice to opt-out of receiving targeted online advertisements from members of the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA), please visit the DAA website at  http://www.aboutads.info/choices/. To learn how you can opt-out of Google’s use of cookies, please visit Google’s Ad Settings at: [https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated]. **

**Tools  on Mobile Devices. ** You can control the tools on your mobile devices. For example, you can turn off the GPS locator or push notification on your phone. Please consult your mobile device’s user guide for instructions on clearing cookies, disabling location services, and disabling push notifications. 

**Do Not Track (“DNT”) Signals.**   Costa does not currently respond to DNT signals but may do so in the future.

**8\. Accessing and Updating your PII**

You may [contact us](https://www.costadelmar.com/us/en/customer-contact/customer-contact.html "Contact Us") to update your PII.  Some Costa Websites may allow you to set up an account and access and update your PII by logging into your account and going to the appropriate section of your account.

**9\. Consent of data Transfer of Non-U.S. Residents**

Costa is based in the United States and our websites are hosted here. If you are visiting our websites from another country, the laws governing the collection and use of PII may be different from the laws of your country. If you decide to visit our websites, or share your PII with Costa, you are agreeing to be governed by the laws of the United States, and you are expressly consenting that the PII you have provided may be transferred to, processed, and stored in the United States. In particular, please note that neither our websites, nor the products or services we offer on our websites, nor any other activities we carry out as set out in this privacy policy are aimed at individuals based in any jurisdiction within the European Economic Area.

**10\. Notice to California Residents - Your California Privacy Rights**

Under California’s "Shine the Light" law, California residents who provide PII in obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from Costa once a calendar year information about the PII we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of PII and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2013 will receive information regarding 2012 sharing activities).

To obtain this information, please [contact us](https://www.costadelmar.com/us/en/customer-contact/customer-contact.html "Contact Us"), with "Request for California Privacy Information" on the subject line and in the body of your message. We will provide the requested information to you at your e-mail address in response.

Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the "Shine the Light" requirements and only information on covered sharing will be included in our response.

**11\. Links to Other Websites**

**Other Costa Websites and Digital Platforms.**  This statement applies only to the Costa Digital Services on which it is posted. Other Costa websites, mobile websites, social media sites and other digital platforms may have different privacy policies so please be sure and read the privacy policy of each Costa website, mobile website, social media site and other digital platform that you visit to understand how Costa collects and uses information and under what circumstances Costa shares information about you collected through that website, mobile website, social media site or other digital platform.

**Third Party Websites and Digital Platforms.**  The Digital Services may contain links to third party sites and digital platforms. Costa is not responsible for the content or policies of such sites and platforms and recommends that you review the privacy policy posted on each third party website and digital platform that you visit.

**12\. Contact Costa to Ask Questions and Provide Feedback Regarding Privacy**

Costa welcomes your questions, comments and concerns about privacy.  Costa is committed to the resolution of concerns or complaints about your privacy and Costa’s collection or use of your PII.  If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or how Costa protects your PII, please [contact us](https://www.costadelmar.com/us/en/customer-contact/customer-contact.html "Contact Us").
